[Music]
In today's fast-paced business
environment, rapid growth brings both
opportunities and hidden risk. As
companies scale at unprecedented speeds,
how can they protect themselves against
the mounting liability challenges that
come with expansion? Welcome to the
policy bazar for business show partnered
by now. I'm Kavita Hapllayal and today
we are going to explore the delicate
balance between innovation and
protection. in uncovering strategies
that help businesses grow confidently
while safeguarding their future. Joining
me in this conversation, we have uh
Namita Roa, vice president and national
head liability credit and speciality
lines Reliance General Insurance, Japal
Single uh group CFO ID Fresh Food, Saja
Pravin Chri, director and head policy
bazar for business. Welcome to the show.
All right. So Namita Saja and Rapal
welcome to this discussion and today we
are going to be talking about uh
liability insurance. Saja uh let's just
get the concept clear. Uh we are talking
about liability risk covers for
corporates and for businesses right. Uh
what all does it entail? See basically
you know uh liability as you understand
the word right? It's about anything and
everything that can come under which is
a probably a financial loss or a kind of
you know a suit that might come arise on
you. Okay. Now financial laws and that
might happen with respect to say there's
a client of yours or there's a you know
corporate which is working with say
another another supplier or say he's
kind of providing some services to other
another client and any kind of financial
loss that that client or say a third
party again you know we're speaking
about corporates and hence I'm taking
example of say a client kind of thing
where the client faces due to any kind
of deficiency in services that you might
have provided or any kind of deficiency
in the kind of products that you were
provided as a part of the supply chain
to them. Or the other example might be
any kind of third party who's not
related to your entity kind of suing you
for any kind of losses that they would
have faced because of your product,
services or something which is related
to it kind of thing. Anything and
everything who takes care of this loss
or who picks up the cost of this loss,
right? That's what liability policies
are about. So there are different kinds
of liability policies which define in
terms of what kind of loss is covered
under what kind of category. So there is
a structure to it. Yeah, there's a
there's a broad structure to it. For
example, for example, let's assume DNO
it's which covers directors and
officers. Now any kind of executive
decisions that directors and officers
are supposed to take kind of uphold
within a corporate and in case of any
kind of loss that might happen to
shareholders or you know other parties
because of that. Now this policy covers
that. Okay. Now versus say errors and
omissions policy which is also called a
professionality policy. These are
predominantly those which for example
there are certain professional judgment
that you kind of do right when you are
in day-to-day job like for example if
you're an architect kind of there are
certain things that you do as part of
your profession kind of tomorrow a
deficiency in that or a small
misjudgment here and there would have
led to something and someone might have
sued you now every company or every
corporate might not require everything
exactly depending on the stage where
they are and depending on the kind of
product or processes that they run so
for example for a tech company which is
kind of working say with a US- based
companies kind of they say that they
need to have a ENO policy which is a
professional policy for sure as part of
their process or you know in order to
win that tender or you know to win that
contract kind of now DNO they might not
ask you for but as a company which is
kind of into business and you it's it's
your duty also to protect your directors
and offices and hence you might want to
have it so that's where the difference
comes from and depending on your need
kind of these products you know you can
look at which product suits your uh
needs the best but having said that
again any category of liability policy
is basically take care of any kind of
financial loss or a suit that might come
on to you because of say deficiency in
services or anything that you might have
done unknowingly or your employees would
have done unknowingly or some fault in
your processes or your product and and
it's a wide wide scope uh that's there
under this how aware are we uh about
this kind of a coverage that uh insurers
offer so Kavita the way we see it
because we are in constant touch with
the insurers and the landscape also is
changing one needs to as much as we are
aware today Tomorrow the landscape
changes, regulations change, geographies
change. So what we do at least uh you
know in my experience whatever we have
done we have constantly stayed in touch
with the insurers, the partners, the
service providers. This has helped us
therefore be aware but our every you
know if I look at industry in large I
think there is a bit more awareness
which needs to be built in. We have seen
examples where um you know because you
know the the the prime importance for
them become day-to-day business what I'm
going to do tomorrow this quarter
particular for listed entities you know
instead of quarter century we start
focusing on quarters so that is where
some of these uh very important parts
but maybe not impacting my tomorrow's
business therefore gets to some extent
overlooked mh when we look at large
groups I think the the awareness is
quite large but as it goes smaller
within the groups when we let's say you
know MSMES particularly I see they are
not aware even within the new age
sectors I see that the awareness could
be probably a little low mhm uh where
the whole industry is helping us is is
you know constantly being in touch with
us uh doing sometimes doing seminars uh
that'sation sessions those are very
helpful so how are you trying to
structure these kind of products because
uh uh as you also highlighted that uh
the awareness level is not exactly what
it's supposed to And uh also it's
something that's seen widely in the
west. Uh big companies already are aware
because they are in line with the
western concept and trend over there.
But then we're talking about new India.
We're talking about vixal bharat where
we have a lot of
msmemes. So uh first how do you
structure these kind of products sectors
sector wise and how do you also help
them uh understand the kind of risk that
they might have? So firstly you know uh
I think this is quite a customized
product but having said that it's a
customized product we don't say that we
don't have solutions formemes or
individuals okay so I'll start with
individuals I'm going to go the you know
uh opposite way not from large
corporates but from individuals with
policy bazar itself we do a lot of work
in reliance for doctors professional
indemnity where we give you know we
cover them you know for their negligence
in their normal day-to-day you know work
profession you know obviously that's a
complete noble cause that they doing and
they need to get protected. So similarly
for you know small and medium
enterprises you can have certain
pre-andigent products which are even
there on websites of companies but it's
just that it's more awareness which will
lead to these companies coming on the
website and start buying these products
and we can we can do a small package or
a small directors and officers for the
directors or a GL policy which you know
which is a public liability you know
basically a slip and trip or anything
which can happen from your premise
liability and see the risk is changing.
Exactly. And you know risks are
emanating from contractual and
regulatory requirements of these
corporates. Beside the main concept of
risk for example I'll speak about the
public liability act which was a statute
recently you know there's been a
legislation that the amount has
increased from 5 crores or 15 crores to
500 crores because you know uh the
government also feels that as a statute
it means wire protection or if we speak
about the consumer protection act which
came you know 2019 which says that every
person who's selling the product not
just who's manufacturing it but
companies like Amazon they're also
responsible you know for example the
products that they sell and there are
vendor programs for e-commerce giants
like that uh there are certain programs
which we've also done for new age tech
companies understanding the model that
they operate in because these companies
do not function function like a large
corporate but they function a little
differently could be aggregators okay
and then uh for something as recent as
crowd strike which we all saw uh so
there is a cloud outage cover which is a
higher version of the cyber insurance
which says that if there's cyber attack
but you know if there's a human error
and uh your data in the cloud gets
affected or there is a you know
interruption in your business because of
the cloud because today most companies
have the data on cloud. Exactly. Uh how
does it affect you? So you can have
complex uh you know solutions stitched
by reinsurers and you know you can even
give fancy covers like cloud outage to
large corporates. Okay. So like I said
it's a combination of three. Your own
requirement, the regulatory landscape
that you operate in and also the
contractual requirements. Okay. So I
think we'll have to adapt to the
increasing risk, the regulations, uh the
you know what is happening in and around
us and ensure that our policies keep
upgrading according to the new
requirements. So that is something I
would want to focus on. I will come back
to you because I want to understand how
do you keep up with the change in in you
know when it comes to sector trends and
even individuals. Uh but before that if
someone is watching the show right now
okay has a business uh what would be the
steps that you would want to recommend
them to get this kind of an insurance
see basically know I think before
getting this insurance or trying to get
into this you know insurance kind of
thing I think the first thing that you
want to understand is where does this
business tack today currently you know
what kind of risk are are are there with
respect to your business whether so
understanding your risk has to be yeah
the first thing is understanding your
risk is very important in terms of are
there risks which emanate from say your
contracts Because that's a basic thing
right something which you would have
signed but you know you would have
overlooked at some point of time saying
that you would have you've been
obligated to kind of give some kind of
guarantees or assurances that tomorrow
in case of a particular loss happening
or a particular incident happening or a
particular product being recalled which
is part of the supply chain then you
have to bear certain loss. Now is that
covered or not which is purely purely
contractual in nature. The second thing
is from a you know uh from from
perspective say are your directors and
officers covered enough or not for any
kind of issues that might come up
tomorrow where your shareholders might
sue you or some other external parties
might sue you from a corporate
governance perspective and and and then
you look at you know say a regulatory
side of it the regulatory side of it
which might say you know again as just
Namika said kind of uh the regulatory
landscape is also changing right with
with respect to data protection act or
other things new things keep coming up
every now and then and depending on
which side
sector are you in you know whether it's
you know se if you're in the financial
side of it or RBI kind of there are new
regulations that keep coming up now with
respect to that are there any new kind
of risks that emanate from the processes
that you have or anything that you would
want to cover yourself okay yeah so then
basis that then you look at which
products might you know kind of suit you
but for that again you know people like
policies of business are there to help
kind of teams right where we can kind of
come in and kind of suggest you bases
your understanding of risk and then what
We also do is once you have your
understanding of risk, we also work with
a wide range of clientele. So we are
able to kind of do a benchmarking kind
of to say okay this size of a say BFSI
segment kind of a client would ideally
look at this kind of a coverage and
these are the products that we do with
them which which might be a combination
of two three products kind of right and
then what kind of coverages do they take
whether it's basis the turnovers or
basis you know whichever numbers are
there that product and then suggest them
what is the right thing for them and
then it's up to the client right now to
take whether they would want to take a
particular size of a cover or not. So
where we recommend today to people that
you know for those who don't have a
claim and who might see that in near
future that you might have a lot of uh
increase in revenue from those
operations or increase in exposure that
might come up to kind of start building
up that coverage from today itself
rather than saying today you have say a
50 cr cover and all of a sudden you're
going to come about couple of years down
the line and say I need a 500 cr cover.
Now it might not be possible for
insurance companies also to give that on
that day. Having said that, it might
also happen that some incident in
between. It might not happen with your
company per se but something would have
happened in your industry in a similar
nature and hence it might impact even
your coverage also getting upgraded
because you you might be saying nothing
happened with my bank or my you know my
company or my processes so why should I
you know not not get this cover but it
doesn't work that way right insurance at
the end of the day is about pooling and
then insurers also pull back with
reinsurers reinsurers would also face
some risks and and you know some kind of
claims from somewhere and then they see
that sector you know altogether in
similar direction kind of a thing so
That's that's where these kind of risks
emanate from. So that's where we we come
up from someone you know who would want
to either look at taking a coverage a
fresh or someone who has a coverage.
What we do is today we kind of try to
benchmark it with respect to others in
the similar category kind of and then
second we also do a kind of gap
analysis. So I really want to go deep in
the quantifying aspect of this risk but
then before that how did you come up
with your risk analysis and what were
the pain areas for you that you
identified. So the way uh I think of it
kavita is like you know risk are of two
types one is defined right we already
know this is a risk and you know people
like politics are all of them help us
covering those risks but there are one
part of the risk which we don't see
right I I feel that risk is something we
don't see and that risk when it triggers
it generally we have seen that it
happens only after it has triggered
sometimes we have not even taken
insurance exactly yeah I'll give you an
example of covid maybe not in a um
insurance example but that risk nobody's
So and therefore nothing was covered and
all of the all of a sudden the world was
sort of thrown at tandem saying that
okay today has happened nobody was
prepared that is because you did not see
once you see the risk I think you are
covered even within the risk that you
have seen people at times or corporates
or like we saw like we spoke about
smaller corporates think about the
probability the possibility right
possibility is there yes but is the
probability less than 0.01% 01%. So then
you start structuring that this okay I
think you know Saja talk about spoke
about cyber etc. I think many of the
corporates think that okay I mean this
is not going to happen for us and not
cover when they cover then they start
looking at the quantum okay should I
take it for 1 cr 2 cr 5
cr you don't you don't know how much is
enough yeah last but not the least you
have taken a cover and every year you
end up just renewing that cover yeah I'm
not using it have you reevaluated saying
that my business has doubled from last
year to this year have I added you know
enough cover there okay yeah another
thing which we see From an industry
perspective, businesses are also
dynamic. Like you know, I think Namita
and Saja both spoke about the
regulation, the change. But businesses
are also dynamic. Yesterday I was doing
one product. Today I could be doing
another product all together. Yesterday
we were present in two geographies.
Today we could be in five more
geographies all together. Yeah.
Yesterday we had one set of customers.
Tomorrow we may have completely
different set of products need to be
flexible that way. And the learning
therefore has to be also continuous
saying that what has changed from last
year to this year. Okay. It should not
become an annual exercise of renewing
the existing policy. Yeah. Yeah. So
quantum is critical. Risk is what we
don't see is critical to not go by
probabilities I think is very critical.
We once you start uh you know uh
bringing in probabilities that is where
the whole sway happens and at the end of
it another thing which I very strongly
believe in
a good solution sometimes may sound
expensive but a bad one can cost a
fortune. So those are the things I think
from a corporate side we look at and and
one whoever is a deciding authority
within the corporate should look at
because his fiduciary duty is to protect
the corporate from all sorts of
possibilities. Exactly. All sort of
probabilities, all sorts of risks and
that is how I would like to see risk as
sure. So we have help over here to
identify the risk aspect in your
business. But how do you help them
quantify that risk? There is specific
benchmarking that you also mention.
interesting question that you asked and
obviously you know we have actials and
you know data you know obviously data is
definitely a part of it but there are
also different ways one is quantifying
your own risk you know like like you
know uh when I was explaining this
concept I mentioned that you know this
is one risk where unlike let's say a
property insurance or let's say a normal
asset insurance you cannot quantify the
exact amount because it could be
uncertain also depending on the kind of
lawsuit which can come on to you for or
or or depending on the propensity of the
cyber attack or the you know extent of
the lawsuit which can come on to you.
For example, tomorrow if a company which
is making tobacco gets a US, you know,
class action suit, you know, because
they manufacturing tobacco and there is
suddenly, you know, there is uh or
there's a cyber attack which comes on
maybe India's largest, you know, I think
on Netflix I was just saying watching a
movie about cyber attack on a company
which is into power and you know which
which can even lead to a business
interruption of let's say days, weeks or
years. So it is difficult to quantify
the exact amount and that's why this
insurance is a little different from you
know asset insurance but uh you know you
definitely have parameters okay
parameters it it could be you know
basically what companies of other size
of your size take in different
geographies or jurisdictions and what
you do where we call a peer benchmarking
which does uh secondly it's definitely
on the operations of your business and
what we see in similar business is the
kind of risk that the businesses pose on
you but we also underneath to understand
your business from you. For example, we
uh you know you know we ask a client as
to how what do you think if there's a
cyber attack? How many days would your
systems be down or you know what's the
kind of revenue you feel you can lose or
example if I'm doing a CGL I look at the
product liability with a pharma company
definitely operating in the US it could
be a class action suit also because
they're operating in that you know
territory. Third, it could also be the
geographies that you're present whether
it's if you have if you're a
multinational operating in let's say
multiple countries then obviously you
are subject to all the geographies or
all the jurisdictions and we spoke of
regulations and the regulations that you
are a part of. Okay. And uh obviously
the fourth was the changing nature of
the business. Yeah. You know we all s
read the Indian bug saga which was first
time in the India but abroad it's a
concept you know it's a concept which is
there you know companies are you know
obviously subject to you know uh these
activists you know and regulators also
encourage because sometimes that helps
them in controlling frauds and also you
know controlling the loopholes also. So
the changing environment that you're a
part of and what I always suggest to my
our clients is or as an institutions
that you have to start somewhere start
with the cover and keep on increasing it
every year and when you are increasing
it if you're growing if you're growing
at let's say 20% or 10% uh you can
increase it but let's say if you are
growing in organically not just in terms
of revenue but in your presence like all
I you know when you read a balance sheet
of a client and you say that okay you
are growing in geographic fees you are
growing in businesses which are more
specialist or you know or in basically
you're also growing in terms of you know
your approach the brand you're you're
you're being acquired by international
brand obviously you need to increase the
cover so it's a combination of various
factors you factor which I just labeled
and obviously it's not one straight
formula so it's difficult for clients
but obviously as insurers and as brokers
uh you cannot set a limit for the client
that's for the client to choose always
but you can always give them a guide as
to these are the parameters and this is
the peer benchmarking and so then the
clients can take their own decision.
Sure any kind of liability that is not
covered today in terms of you know how
do you put it there'll be certain things
which for example anything that might
happen due to let's say the company
itself might getting be involved
knowingly being involved in a particular
thing right these kind of things come
into litigations or between even the
insurance company or anyone also uh let
me put this way today let's assume under
liability policy which we spoke about
today right let if it's a errors and
omissions kind of a policy that we
promotional indemnity or errors and
omissions something that might have
happened due to an error kind of a thing
or or a misjudgment or you know of of
your professional who's let's assume if
you're a law firm you're suggesting
something to a firm and there's a
judgment error that happened or a miss
that has happened by mistake kind of
thing or similarly the architect example
that we took about or let's assume as
part of your profession you were doing
something but you didn't expect that to
happen and you you suggested something
and it turned out adverse those would be
covered but then you know you
willingfully you know kind of doing some
kind of uh act act within that uh for
example this other thing which we speak
about rather than speak about something
liability which is not covered I think
we should more about speak about
situations which we see today where
certain uh how do you put coverages
don't get triggered on on something
happening for example within these
policies for example there are PR costs
now what is the kind of PR cost that you
have seen for example right now in a PR
cost let's assume some kind of a
directors and office policy got
triggered a claim got triggered but the
limit of PR PR cost that you put in is
very small. But for example, tomorrow
you you being into for example you're a
consultancy business. You're a
consulting business uh and and and
primarily your PR is or or you know your
brand image is what makes your business
in a consulting business right unlike an
FMCG product where your product is being
used day in day out. Uh so in such a
case if your PR costs are so low which I
put up in that policy is a limit kind of
thing then what you're going to end up
spending out of your pocket is going to
be so huge and not not getting out of
the policy as such. Right? So these are
certain things which I would say rather
than saying not covered what are the
coverages that you're taking with
respect to the risks that you have is is
what we have seen at least in some of
the cases. I I remember very recent I
think 2 3 months back is one of the
things where we again you know had a
similar kind of a nature I would say
kind of where you know probably a DNO
kind of a policy which which is there
with one of the client and they wanted
to kind of claim you know the PR costs
against that but then in that case what
happened is the claim itself did not get
triggered there was some incident that
happened and as a result they were to
they they had to kind of spend a lot on
PR kind of a thing but in that case the
in director's office is the first thing
is there has to be a suit against the
directors and officers and then things
have to trigger out of it. Right? So
similar to any other insurance like once
that incident gets triggered then the
rest of things also will follow but then
without the incident itself getting
triggered then things would not happen
of that sort. So these are the kind of
things that you have to take care of uh
when you know when you're looking at
this specifically of you know whether
something that gets covered or like the
way you asked what is the thing that
does not that doesn't get covered kind
right I think for that we will need one
more show on this particular topic
because I'm done with my timing. Thank
you so much for being on the show today.
And uh that's a wrap. Thank you so much
for watching. Goodbye.
[Music]